Md Mahfuz Ali

6/3, Block D, Lalmatia, Dhaka. Phone: +88017166356425 Email: mahfuz.s.mail@gmail.com

Date of birth: **17-6-1991** Nationality: **Bangladeshi**

PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT:

Detail oriented professional with extensive experience in Software Development, Software project management and excellent problem-solving skills. I am currently working for Synergy Interface Ltd. as Project Coordinator. I have total job experience of 6 years in Web Development, Hardware & Network trouble shooting and Teaching. I have completed **M. Sc. in Computer Science** from **Jahangirnagar University**, Dhaka, Bangladesh. Seeking to take the next career step with respected organization dedicated to world class quality. Born leader with the ability to lead teams to process and manage large volumes without compromising service or quality. My verbal communication skills and positive attitude makes me an effective communicator with my team members.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS ARE:

- ✓ Lots of web based Creative Projects including Govt. project.
- ✓ Well organized
- ✓ Able to prioritize and generate results to achieve organizational objective within time and budgetary expectations.
- ✓ Dedicated and focused
- ✓ Able to prioritize and complete multiple tasks and flow through to achieve project goals.
- ✓ Experience in organizational diagnosis and design and facilitation have large-scale events and staff development activities.
- ✓ An independent and self-motivated professional with excellent research and writing skills;
- ✓ Able to grow positive relationships with clients and colleagues at all organizational levels.

RELEVANT KEY SKILL:

• Structured Programming Language : C

• Object-Oriented Programming Languages: C++, PHP

• Web Programming Languages : HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Java Script,

jquery, Ajax, Angular JS, Node JS and

PHP

• PHP Frameworks : CodeIgniter and Laravel

CMS : WordpressRDBMS : MySql, Sql

• Concepts : Wamp, Xampp, Cpanel

Modeling Languages : E-R Diagram

• Designing Tools : Photoshop, Illustrator

Maintenance : Hardware assembling, Problem solving

and hardware operations

Operating System : Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8,

Linux & Ubuntu



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

1) Cloud Production Limited, Dhaka. (February, 2020 - Present)

Position: Team Leader (Software Department)

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining and monitoring project plans, project schedules, and work hours.
- Work with developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts on technical issues including software system design and maintenance.
- Consulting with departments or customers on project status and proposals.
- Directing software programming design algorithms and flowcharts and documentation for development.
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications.
- Recommend and execute improvements.
- Create technical documentation for reference and reporting.
- Documenting and following up on important actions and decisions from meetings.
- Determining project changes.
- Assess project risks and issues and provide solutions where applicable.
- Ensure stakeholder views are managed towards the best solution.
- Create a project management calendar for fulfilling each goal and objective.

2) Synergy Interface, Dhaka. (July, 2018 - Present)

Position: Project Coordinator (Software Department)

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining and monitoring project plans, project schedules, work hours, budgets and expenditures.
- Working with developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts on technical issues including software system design and maintenance.
- Consulting with departments or customers on project status and proposals.
- Directing software programming design algorithms and flowcharts and documentation for development.
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications.
- Recommend and execute improvements.
- Create technical documentation for reference and reporting.
- Documenting and following up on important actions and decisions from meetings.
- Determining project changes.
- Assess project risks and issues and provide solutions where applicable.

3) Synergy Interface, Dhaka. (February, 2016 – June, 2018)

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Designing and developing software systems using analysis, measure outcomes and design consequences.
- Writing and implementing efficient code.
- Testing and evaluating new programs.
- Developing quality assurance procedures
- Troubleshoot, debug, maintain and upgrade existing systems.
- Preparing reports on programming project specifications, activities, or status.
- Conferring with project managers to obtain information on limitations or

capabilities.

- Verify and deploy programs and systems
- Training users.

4) Next Technology & Engineering, Dhaka. (July, 2014 - November-2015)

Position: Software Support Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Talking through requirements with clients
- Testing software and fixing problems
- Maintaining systems once they're up and running
- Being a part of technical designing
- Integrate software components
- Writing program codes for reference and reporting

5) IBAIS University. (June 2013 – June 2015)

Position: Teaching Assistant

Responsibilities:

- Assist teachers with lesson preparation by getting materials ready.
- Conduct classes & Help Students with academic syllabus.
- Oversee students during non-classroom times including in-between classes, during lunch, and on field excursions.
- Collaborate with lead teachers to recognize issues students are facing and recommend solutions
- Help supervise students in class, between classes, during lunch and recess, and on field trips

OTHER EXPERIENCES:

1) New Model Degree College and University

Position: Lecturer

2) IBAIS University (Part Time)

Position: Lecturer

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS:

2016 M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering,

Jahangirnagar University, Dhaka.

Passing Year: 2016

2015 **B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering,** 2015

IBAIS University, Dhaka. Passing Year: 2015

2010 Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C)

Concentration: Science

Dinajpur Govt. Collage, Dinajpur.

2006 **Secondary School Certificate Examination**

Concentration: Science

Saint Philips High school, Dinajpur.

TRAINING / WORKSHOP:

1) Full Stack Web Development

Institute: BASIS Institute of technology and Management

Duration: 90 Hours (30/07/2017-31/10/2017)

2) Customer Support & Services

Institute: Bangladesh Association of Software & Information & management

supported by Skill for Employment Investment Program (SEIP) Finance Division,

Ministry of Finance. Govt. of Bangladesh

Duration: 30th October 2016 – 25th November 2016

3) Training program on Awareness session on CMMI, ISO 9001 & ISO/IEC 27001

Institute: United Certification Services Limited (UNICERT)

Date: 8th April 2017

4) Workshop on Oracle Institute: DATAPARK **Duration:** 2 Days

5) Red Hat System Administration I

Institute: IBAIS University

Duration: 15 Days

WEB APPLICATIONS AND DYNAMIC WEBSITE DEVELOPED:

Sl.	Client's Name	Application Type	Application Developed
1.	Mirpur Cant. Public School & Collage	Software	Teacher Assessment Software
2.	Care Nutrition Bangladesh	Software	Web Based Sales Tracking System (DMS).
3.	Smart Technologies	Software	E-warranty System
4.	Personal Project	Software	Tiffin Management Software
5.	Personal Project	Software	Hospital Management Software
6.	Personal Project	Software	Online Dealer Point Management
7.	ICT Ministry Bangladesh	Website with	Design, Development & Maintenance of
	http://askrambler.com	CMS	Tourism Website & Apps
8.	Fuad Almuqtadir http://fuadmusic.com	Professional portfolio websites	Design and Development of a Professional portfolio websites With Content Management System(CMS)
9.	Agile 1 Tech http://bdlist24.com/demo/	Website with CMS	Design, Development of a classified website.
10.	Bangladesh Broadcast Systems https://www.bbs-bd.com	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
11.	Pharm-D Rx http://www.pharmd-rx.com	Website with Word press	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
12.	Humanity For Human http://h4hworld.org	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
13.	Keystone Medical Urgent Care https://kmucpa.com	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
14.	Accelerated Surgical Center http://www.acceleratedsurgical.com om	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
15.	Bloom Field Health SERVICES https://bloomfieldhealth.org	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
16.	Englewood Diagnostic And Imaging Center https://englewoodimaging.com	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)
17.	Barnert Surgical Center http://www.barnertsurgical.com	Website with CMS	Design and Development of Corporate Web site With Content Management System(CMS)